朱妍欣 Zhu Yanxin

r.piggy.lol

Fullstack Developer

An experienced full-stack engineer with 3 years of professional experience (1.5 years in React frontend and 1.5 years in Python backend). With a bachelor's degree in Information Security, I bring a unique perspective to product design and a keen sensitivity to UI aesthetics. I am well-equipped to support your lab in maintaining course systems and contribute as a seasoned full-stack engineer.

Contacts Profile

anigiscur@gmail.com https://github.com/anig1scur

https://piggy.lol/users/ac3r - a mastodon instance

Chinese (native)

served by myself

Education Language

Bachelor's degree, Information Security

GPA 3.52 | Communication University of China (2017 - 2021) English (IELTS 6.0 / DET 115)

Work Experience

Fullstack Developer • Douban

Nov 2020 - Now | Beijing

- Integral maintenance contributor for Douban's core products, including Book, Movie, and Music.
- Collaborate closely with PM, UX and other engineers to develop new features for Douban's web and app platforms.
- Engage in optimizing logic and iterating tools to assist Douban in liberating legacy code from historical burdens.

After serving as a backend intern for 8 months followed by a year as a backend development engineer, I applied internally within the company to transition to a frontend role. This decision stemmed from my stronger preference for frontend work and my passion in this area. As a result, I have gained experience in both frontend and backend development.

Douban Annual Ranking and Visualization Editing Platform Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

This project is the new architecture for Douban's annual ranking, revamped at the end of 2023. I was responsible for both the frontend and backend parts of this system along with another colleague. It consists of two main parts: 1. An editing backend for operations staff. 2. Rankings pages for users (eg. **Douban Book Annual 2023**)

- 1. **Technology Stack** Frontend: Utilized the React.js framework, incorporating hooks, TypeScript, Ant Design, and Lottie for animations. Backend: Built with Python and Flask.
- 2. Widget-based Page System Implemented a page structure that supports multiple widgets, enhancing the reuse of the annual ranking. This design reduces the workload for developing future rankings, as new features can be added by creating new widgets within the existing framework.
- **3. Responsive Design** Developed adaptive previews for both mobile and PC, with distinct editing and preview modes. The WYSIWYG interface significantly improves the efficiency of the operations team in editing the annual rankings.

Internship • SAP Cloud Platform

June 2020 - Nov 2020 | Beijing

- Developer of SAP automatic framework focusing on Android part
- Use NativeScript to develop internal tools for designing app on both platforms more effortlessly.
- Member of 2020 SAP Girls Power Tech

Knowledge & Skills

- Proficient in JavaScript (ES6 / TypeScript) with a deep understanding of React and its ecosystem.
- Understanding of layout techniques like Flex/Grid and knowledge of modularization solutions like CSS Modules.
- Familiar with bundling tools such as Webpack and Vite.
- Familiar with Python web frameworks, eg. Flask and Quixote and Experienced of coding against RESTful APIs.
- With an in-depth understanding of computer architecture and computer networking, navigating daily tasks using Arch Linux as my operating system.
- Possess foundational knowledge of algorithms, data structures principles and time complexity.